<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Lead with Storytelling</title>
    <link>https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk</link>
    <description>Lead with Storytelling is a captivating podcast hosted by Sochi Azuh, where he delves into the world of storytelling with a diverse array of creative business leaders, writers, and content creators. This podcast is a treasure trove for anyone seeking to master the art, science, and business of crafting and sharing impactful stories.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Chisom Ezeh - Storytelling for Empowerment</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lYoetIkpiMI</link>
      <description>In this episode of Lead with Storytelling, we're excited to speak with Chisom Ezeh, an award-winning book publishing expert, founder of The Publishing Pad, and one of Canada's Top 100 Black Women to Watch in 2024. Chisom shares insights on book publishing, personal growth, and the power of storytelling.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lYoetIkpiMI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Nicole Vair - Storytelling Through Various Sectors</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=po37Y-G94WQ&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=2</link>
      <description>In this episode of Lead with Storytelling, we’re excited to chat with Nicole Vair, a seasoned storyteller and marketing professional. With a background in journalism and a passion for brand storytelling, Nicole has crafted impactful campaigns for organizations across various sectors, from health and wellness to regional growth. Currently, she leads marketing efforts at Envision Saint John: The Regional Growth Agency, where she uses storytelling to amplify the unique stories that make the Saint John Region thrive.

Nicole dives deep into the art of place branding, sharing her insights on how storytelling can drive community pride, attract new residents, and create a sense of belonging. This conversation is packed with practical tips on weaving stories that resonate and inspire—whether you're working in public sector marketing, community development, or corporate branding.

In this episode, Nicole explores:
🌎 Place Branding Through Storytelling: How stories can shape the identity of a place and connect with both locals and newcomers.
🏡 Building Pride of Place: Using storytelling to highlight the people and organizations driving growth in the Saint John Region.
🎬 Campaign Success Stories: A behind-the-scenes look at impactful campaigns, including a powerful Shell ad and Envision Saint John’s Growth Stories series.
💼 Transition from Journalism to Marketing: How Nicole’s background in journalism has informed her approach to brand storytelling.
🔍 Strategies for Authenticity: Key elements of authentic storytelling that drive engagement and impact.
💡 Creating a Lasting Impression: How to craft stories that resonate long after they’ve been told.

Show Notes:
📲 Connect with Nicole on LinkedIn: /nicole-vair-0b816a72
📹 Watch the Campaign Video Referenced by Nicole: Shell Campaign Video • Katie’s Powering Homes | #MakeTheFuture
🌱 Explore Envision Saint John’s Growth Stories: Showcasing the people and organizations building the Saint John Region’s future https://www.envisionsaintjohn.com/gro...

Discover how Nicole combines strategic storytelling with a deep commitment to her community, creating campaigns that truly make an impact.

🔗 Listen, learn, and find inspiration for your own storytelling journey!</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=po37Y-G94WQ</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Ifeanyi Chidi - Exploring Authenticity and Evolution in Nollywood</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lYoetIkpiMI&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk</link>
      <description>Exploring Authenticity and Evolution in Nollywood with Ifeanyi Barbara Chidi, Creator and Head Writer of Cheta M and Diiche

In this episode, we’re thrilled to have Ifeanyi Barbara Chidi, an acclaimed Nigerian writer, director, and producer whose work has made waves across the Nollywood industry. As the founder of The Crazy Giggle Company and the creator of Cheta M and Diiche—Showmax’s first Nigerian epic series and limited drama series, respectively—Fifi has redefined what it means to tell authentic Nigerian stories.

With a deep commitment to portraying Nigerian culture through film, Fifi has contributed to some of Nollywood’s biggest hits, including Crime and Justice Lagos, Dilemma, Riona, Slum King, and Hush. Named as one of the 100 most influential people in Nollywood by YNaija and Ebony Life, Fifi’s career is a testament to her talent and dedication to elevating African storytelling.

In this insightful conversation, Fifi dives into:

🎬 Nollywood’s Evolution: The transformation of Nigerian cinema and its impact on African storytelling.
🌟 Legacy of Amaka Igwe: Reflections on one of Nigeria’s most influential filmmakers and her lasting influence.
📚 Authenticity in Storytelling: Defining what it means to tell "authentic" Nigerian stories in an evolving industry.
🎭 Stereotypes in Cinema: How they affect character development and the strategies to overcome them.
🎨 Balancing Art and Commerce: Navigating the need for commercial success while maintaining artistic integrity in Nollywood.
🔊 Diverse Voices: The importance of varied perspectives in storytelling to reflect the true depth of Nigerian culture.
🌍 Influence of Nollywood: How Nigerian cinema shapes cultural narratives and societal perceptions both locally and globally.
✍️ Improving Storytelling Quality: Practical strategies to elevate storytelling in Nollywood and ensure a lasting impact.

Show Notes:

🔗 Connect with Ifeanyi Barbara Chidi on LinkedIn: /ifeanyi-barbara-chidi-b19b0428
🎬 Work with The Crazy Giggle Company: /thecrazygiggle

Join us as we explore the power of authentic storytelling in Nollywood, and discover how Fifi is championing a new era of African cinema. Tune in for an inspiring conversation on culture, identity, and the future of Nigerian filmmaking!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5mLk-Qs3y_Y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Oje Ojeaga - Unveiling the Power of Storytelling in the Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kkzuBUgUeU8&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=4</link>
      <description>In this episode, we are thrilled to sit down with Oje Ojeaga, the visionary CEO and Chief Creative Officer of Up in The Sky, Nigeria's top storytelling agency. With nearly two decades of experience, Oje has made an indelible mark in the creative industry, earning accolades from international platforms like the Loeries, The Pitcher Awards, and the Berlin Short Film Festival.

Oje has masterfully blended brand strategy and storytelling to create unforgettable campaigns for global powerhouses such as Google, Coca-Cola, The Mastercard Foundation, Arla Dano, and The World Health Organization. His cinematic approach to storytelling has redefined marketing, showing how narratives can build powerful connections between brands and their audiences.

In this insightful conversation, Oje dives into:

🔗 Storytelling and Brand Strategy: How to use storytelling to forge deeper connections with your audience.
🤖 Leveraging AI in Advertising: How AI is transforming storytelling and brand engagement.
📈 Measuring Impact: How strategic storytelling drives business growth and measurable results.
🖥️ Adapting Narratives for Digital Platforms: How to maintain authenticity across diverse channels.
🎨 Balancing Creativity and Data: Finding the sweet spot between creative expression and data-driven insights.
🚀 Future Trends: What’s next for storytelling in an AI-powered world.

Show Notes:
   📚 Download The Monday Memos by Oje Ojeaga and subscribe to his newsletter: https://bit.ly/46clhNN
   💼 Connect with Oje Ojeaga on LinkedIn: /ojeojeaga

Tune in for a deep dive into the future of advertising, where creative storytelling meets data-driven strategy, and learn how your brand can thrive in the digital landscape!</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kkzuBUgUeU8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Priya Bates - A Journey in Storytelling</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2FHZgTP-7HQ&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=5</link>
      <description>In this episode of the Lead with Storytelling podcast, we are thrilled to welcome Priya Bates, an award-winning professional communicator and President of Inner Strength Communication. Priya brings her vast experience as a co-host of the Leader Like Me podcast and her work with clients across various sectors, including technology, retail, finance, government, and education.

Priya holds impressive credentials as an accredited Business Communicator (ABC) and one of the first Certified Strategic Communication Management Professionals (SCMP) globally. She is also an International Association of Business Communicators (IABC) Fellow, a prestigious global lifetime achievement award in the field. Based in Toronto, Canada, Priya shares her invaluable insights into storytelling and communication strategies.

Join us as we delve into Priya's journey and explore the value of inclusive communications, the power of storytelling in creating inclusive communities and workplaces, and the importance of representation.

Advert mentioned in the podcast (Eating together / Loblaws Commercial): • #EatTogether Commercial

🌐 Priya's Website: https://innerstrengthcommunication.co...
🎙️ Priya's Podcast: A Leader Like Me https://aleaderlikeme.com/podcast/
📚 Priya's Book: Effective Internal Communication For Diversity, Equity and Inclusion | Building a Culture of Inclusivity https://www.amazon.ca/Building-Cultur...

Stay true, and lead with storytelling!</description>
      <pubDate>Tues, 02 Jul 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2FHZgTP-7HQ</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Rishad Tobaccowala - Storytelling and the Future of Marketing</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lYoetIkpiMI&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk</link>
      <description>In this episode of Lead with Storytelling, host Sochi Azuh chats with Rishad Tobaccowala, a leading business strategist and author. With over 40 years of experience, including his role as Chief Growth Officer at Publicis Groupe, Rishad offers valuable insights into the future of marketing, the power of storytelling, and balancing innovation with human values.

Rishad, author of "Restoring the Soul of Business," discusses the role of data and storytelling in brand building. This episode is a must-listen for marketing professionals, business leaders, and anyone interested in technology and human behavior.

Tune in for Rishad's book recommendations at the end of the podcast.

🌐 Rishad's Website: https://rishadtobaccowala.com/
📰 Rishad's Newsletter: The Future Does Not Fit in the Containers of the Past Subscribe Here https://substack.com/@rishad
🎙️ Rishad's Podcast: What Next? Listen on Spotify https://open.spotify.com/show/5B7OzFC...
📚 Rishad's Book: Restoring the Soul of Business Get it on Amazon https://www.amazon.com/Restoring-Soul...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OG6uf7cRTGo</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Sochi Azuh - Why Tell Stories?</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3VwJAVcdKmE&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=7</link>
      <description>Welcome to Lead with Storytelling, the podcast where Sochi Azuh explores the world of storytelling with creative business leaders, writers, and content creators. In this debut episode, "Why Tell Stories?", we discuss the passion behind storytelling, its impact, and our podcast's goals.

Lead with Storytelling features enriching interviews with guests from various fields, offering insights on using storytelling to drive personal and professional success. This episode sets the stage for what's to come, explaining why storytelling is vital and transformative.

Whether you're an aspiring writer, marketing professional, or storytelling enthusiast, you'll find valuable insights here. 

Subscribe, leave a review on Apple Podcasts, and share your thoughts to help us create more captivating content.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3VwJAVcdKmE</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Lorraine Peters - Building Bridges between Cultures</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gp4JPTBxVDw&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=8</link>
      <description>Unlock the power of storytelling in leadership with our guest, Lorraine Peters! 🌟 Join us for an insightful chat where Lorraine shares her journey as a leader, storyteller, and successful business person. Discover how she utilizes her diverse experiences, including a former modeling career, fitness expertise, 5X pageant winner, and entrepreneurship, to empower newcomers in Canada. 🌎

🔥 Highlights:
Lorraine's unique lens on achieving human potential.
Accelerating newcomers' integration in Canada.
Power of Storytelling to shape corporate culture
Insights from her impressive journey in modeling, fitness, pageantry, sales, and entrepreneurship.
Book Recommendations and Chats.

👉 Don't miss this episode of "Lead with Storytelling" to gain valuable perspectives and be inspired by Lorraine's incredible story! 🚀

🌐 Connect with Lorraine:
Website: https://www.lmodelscanada.com/about
LinkedIn: /lorrainegilmorepeters
Instagram: /lorraine_peters

🔍 About Lorraine Peters:
Lorraine Peters is not just a wife, mother, and grandmother, but also a dynamic businessperson. With a passion for achieving one's fullest human potential, she leverages her strengths and talents developed over the past 40 years to assist newcomers in accelerating their integration into Canada. Lorraine's diverse background, including a former modeling career, fitness expertise, 5X pageant winner, sales management, and entrepreneurship, provides a unique lens through which she conveys her insightful thinking. An avid reader, gardener, fitness enthusiast, model/actor, Lorraine is poised to make history by competing at one of the most prominent pageants worldwide in the Summer of 2024 at the age of 58.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gp4JPTBxVDw</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Caine Prize Winners Mame Diene and Woppa Diallo</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kwBM4P9dAv0&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=9</link>
      <description>In this enlightening conversation, we sit down with Mame Bougouma Diene and Woppa Diallo, the husband-and-wife duo behind the Caine Prize-winning short story, "A Soul of Small Places." In this engaging interview, we explore the layers and depths of their lyrical take on a compelling theme.

🖋️ About Mame Bougouma Diene:
Mame Diene is a Franco-Senegalese American, making waves in the literary world. A humanitarian based in Pretoria, he is the francophone spokesperson for the African Speculative Fiction Society, and the French language editor for Omenana Magazine. He's also a regular at Strange Horizons. Mame's writings span across various prestigious publications and anthologies. Notably, his novelette "The Satellite Charmer" and "Ogotemmeli's Song" have been translated into multiple languages. He was nominated for several Nommo Awards, and his debut collection "Dark Moons Rising on a Starless Night" was a contender for the 2019 Splatterpunk Award.

📚 About Woppa Diallo:
Woppa Diallo is not just an author but a champion for human rights and women's empowerment. A lawyer specializing in human rights and peace promotion, she founded the Association pour le Maintien des Filles à l'Ecole (AMFE) at just fifteen. Her work focuses on ensuring equal education for girls, combating gender-based stereotypes, and supporting victims of gender-based violence in Matam, Senegal.

⭐ "A Soul of Small Places" - Read the Story:
🔗https://www.caineprize.com/s/A-Soul-o...


🤝 Supporting AMFE - Making a Difference Together:
Woppa Diallo's dedication to social change and women's rights is truly inspirational. Her NGO, Association Pour Le Maintien des Filles à L'Ecole (AMFE), is a beacon of hope for many young girls in Senegal. By supporting AMFE, you can help ensure that every girl receives the education and opportunities they deserve. Let's join hands to make a lasting impact! Learn more and support this noble cause: [https://www.amfe-senegal.com/]

➡️ Don't forget to subscribe for more insightful interviews with leading literary figures. Hit the bell icon to stay updated!

👍 Like | 💬 Comment | 🔄 Share

~
Support the Channel:

📬 Newsletter: https://sochiazuh.com/#newsletter
🤝 Collaborate: sochi.azuh@gmail.com
☕ Buy Me Coffee: https://buymeacoffee.com/sochiazuh

***
🔔 SUBSCRIBE for more content like this.
 
👋 COME SAY HI!

📸 Instagram | /sochiazuh
🐦 Twitter | /sochiazuh
🎵 TikTok | https://www.tiktok.com/sochiazuh
💼 LinkedIn | /sochiazuh</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kwBM4P9dAv0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Yagazie Eguare - Art of Storytelling Through Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vCzx6jaWkA0&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=10</link>
      <description>A captivating conversation with Yagazie Eguare, the visionary founder of Gazmadu Studios and an award-winning photographer. In this conversation, Yagazie shares her inspiring journey into the world of storytelling through the art of photography. Discover how she uses her lens to capture the essence of life's myriad narratives, from everyday moments to profound experiences.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vCzx6jaWkA0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Award-Winning Filmmaker James Omokwe - The Art of African Storytelling</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U26jQpaVno0&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=11</link>
      <description>Join us in this captivating interview with the renowned Nigerian filmmaker and storyteller, James Omokwe, as he delves deep into the art of storytelling and the richness of African narratives. With a passion for weaving tales that resonate with audiences worldwide, James has earned acclaim for his compelling films and thought-provoking narratives.

#AfricanStorytelling #FilmmakerInterview #JamesOmokwe #AfricanCinema #StorytellingArt #AfricanNarratives #NigerianFilmmaker #AwardWinningFilms</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U26jQpaVno0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Obinna Okerekeocha - A Journey in Storytelling</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vPUhCrZJEY0&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=12</link>
      <description>Obinna Okerekeocha is one of the leading creative directors in Nigeria rising branded entertainment scenes as he heads the creative team at RedTV.

He is an artist, movie maker and a musician with an strong background in advertising and second generation ad man.

In this episode, I sit with Obinna to discuss his journey into media, his passions in film making, art, creativity and storytelling in general.

Topics from the show include:
✔️ How to differentiate yourself as a storyteller
✔️ Obinna’s journey to being one of the top creative directors in the media scene
✔️ What would he do if he had unlimited resources.

💌 Mail/subscribe to Sochi’s Newsletter: https://griotnotes.com/about-griot-no...
📍 My blog on Marketing, Storytelling and Culture: https://griotnotes.com 
📍 Twitter: /sochiazuh  
📍 Instagram: /sochiazuh </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vPUhCrZJEY0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Yagazie Eguare - Art of Storytelling Through Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vCzx6jaWkA0&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=10</link>
      <description>A captivating conversation with Yagazie Eguare, the visionary founder of Gazmadu Studios and an award-winning photographer. In this conversation, Yagazie shares her inspiring journey into the world of storytelling through the art of photography.

Discover how she uses her lens to capture the essence of life's myriad narratives, from everyday moments to profound experiences.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vCzx6jaWkA0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Award-Winning Filmmaker James Omokwe - The Art of African Storytelling</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U26jQpaVno0&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=11</link>
      <description>Join us in this captivating interview with the renowned Nigerian filmmaker and storyteller, James Omokwe, as he delves deep into the art of storytelling and the richness of African narratives. With a passion for weaving tales that resonate with audiences worldwide, James has earned acclaim for his compelling films and thought-provoking narratives.

#AfricanStorytelling #FilmmakerInterview #JamesOmokwe #AfricanCinema #StorytellingArt #AfricanNarratives #NigerianFilmmaker #AwardWinningFilms</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U26jQpaVno0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead with Storytelling w/ Obinna Okerekeocha - A Journey in Storytelling</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vPUhCrZJEY0&amp;list=PL9GWHs0T9C9jt-qX2qlaIQ7K1fouzZpNk&amp;index=12</link>
      <description>Obinna Okerekeocha is one of the leading creative directors in Nigeria rising branded entertainment scenes as he heads the creative team at RedTV.

He is an artist, movie maker and a musician with a strong background in advertising and second generation ad man.

In this episode, I sit with Obinna to discuss his journey into media, his passions in film making, art, creativity and storytelling in general.

Topics from the show include:
✔️ How to differentiate yourself as a storyteller
✔️ Obinna’s journey to being one of the top creative directors in the media scene
✔️ What would he do if he had unlimited resources.

💌 Mail/subscribe to Sochi’s Newsletter: https://griotnotes.com/about-griot-no...
📍 My blog on Marketing, Storytelling and Culture: https://griotnotes.com 
📍 Twitter: /sochiazuh  
📍 Instagram: /sochiazuh</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vPUhCrZJEY0</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
